American Council of Railroad Women Records, 1944-1977
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
American Council of Railroad Women records
1944-1977
American Council of Railroad Women
MS 345
18 boxes (10 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
An organization of women holding supervisory positions in railroad personnel and service. The records provide insight into the attitudes and motivations of a group of professional women organized for their mutual benefit at a time when most women had "jobs" rather than "careers." Material includes correspondence, minutes, reports, publications, photographs, scrapbooks, and other material which document its history and activities from its founding until 1977.
In 1944, a small group of women holding supervisory positions in railroad personnel and service held informal meetings in Chicago to discuss their changing roles in the railroad industry during wartime. Over the course of several meetings, they decided that they needed a permanent organization, and in September 1944 twenty-eight women voted to form the National Association of Railroad Women. (The name was changed to American Association of Railroad Women in 1952.) Unprepared by the railroads for promotions to management positions previously held by men, the women organized themselves "to provide a medium of exchange of ideas and experiences relative to our work; to discuss improvements in service and to plan for the better utilization of womanpower in railroading."
Membership eligibility was originally limited to women holding personnel or passenger service positions. Later, it was extended to include women employed in the United States and Canada as corporate officers, assistants and secretaries to presidents, lawyers, magazine editors, engineers, traffic representatives, personnel supervisors, public relations staffs, special representatives, and special investigators.
The council's annual spring and fall meetings include the transaction of business, educational sessions, and entertainment. Throughout its history, the council consistently sought the approval of, and received support from, railroad management, which has contributed senior executives to the sessions as speakers and seminar leaders. Early reports and discussions covered such topics as "education of the travelling public" and "new and improved methods and equipment for cleaning both the exteriors and interiors of trains." Later meetings reflected the evolving membership interests, emphasizing legislative lobbying (including support for the Equal Rights Amendment), and such professional development topics as corporate decision making.
The records of the ACRW consist of ten linear feet of correspondence, minutes, reports, publications, photographs, scrapbooks, and other material documenting its history and activities from its founding until 1977. The records provide some insight into the attitudes and motivations of a group of professional women organized for their mutual benefit at a time when most women had "jobs" rather than "careers."
The bulk of the material consists of meeting minutes (including speeches and miscellaneous material distributed at meetings); and membership applications and correspondence. The codebooks, assembled by the Governing Committee as an easily-accessed information source, partially duplicate the minutes, as they are compilations of similar types of material. The officers' correspondence, which largely concerns meeting arrangements and membership eligibility and recruitment, is most complete for the 1950s and 1970s, fragmentary in the 1960s, and non-existent for the earliest years. The membership files reflect the involvement in membership matters of both the Governing Committee and Membership Committee. They include individuals considered for membership, as well as those who actually joined the ACRW.
The committee files are far from complete; apparently only scattered documentation of the Legislative, Publicity, and Public Relations committees has been retained. Other committees, including Archives, Service, Housing and Transportation, and Nominating, are represented only by their reports in the minutes.
This collection is organized into ten series:
I. Constitution and Bylaws
II. Codebooks
III. Minutes
IV. Meeting Files
V. Officers' Correspondence
VI. Membership Applications and Correspondence
VII. Committees
VIII. Publications
IX. Photographs
X. History
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection with no additional restrictions.
Additions to the Collection
Periodic additions to collection are expected.
History of the Collection
Betty Royon, ACRW member, arranged for the organization's donation of its records in 1972. Additional shipments arrived in 1973 and 1980. Prior to their donation, the records were in the custody of various ACRW historians and other officers.
Search Terms
American Council of Railroad Women--History--Sources; Railroads--Employees--History--Sources; Women railroad employees--History--Sources; Women in the professions--History--20th century--Sources
- Series I. CONSTITUTION AND BYLAWS, 1945, 1948, 1956, 1971
  This series consists of booklets compiling bylaws and roster (1945); constitution and bylaws (1948); and several typescripts of later amendments. The records are arranged chronologically. Other versions (1955-1973) are included in the Codebooks (Series II).
- Series II. CODEBOOKS, 1955-73
  The codebooks were compiled by the Governing Committee members to serve as a "useful tool for future Governing Committees". They include the constitution and bylaws; lists of officers; members and their status; financial transactions; and records of decisions and actions on everything from membership eligibility to the cost of gummed labels. The series is arranged chronologically.
- Series III. MINUTES, 1945-76
  This series contains minutes of the Governing Committee, spring (or regional), and fall (or annual) meetings. Starting in 1973, the ACRW maintained related materials, such as programs, agendas, speeches, etc., in the minutes sequence. For pre-1973 materials of this sort, see the Meeting Files (series IV). The Governing Committee minutes also include agendas and memoranda; the general minutes include committee reports. The series is arranged chronologically.
- Series IV: MEETING FILES, 1947-77
  This series contains programs and menus; agendas; and correspondence about meeting arrangements and follow-up thank yous (1959, 1968-1977). From l973 on, materials of this sort are also maintained in the Minutes (Series III), resulting in some overlap between the series. The series is arranged chronologically.
- Series V: OFFICERS' CORRESPONDENCE, 1951-77
  This series contains little material from the organization's earliest years and is fragmentary for the 1960s. The bulk of correspondence dates from the 1950s and 1970s. Juva Dennis' file was received as a unit and has been maintained as such. It contains her correspondence from the time she joined the ACRW in l969 through her tenures as secretary (1970-72), second vice-president (1972-73), member-at-large (1974-75), and president (1976-77). Her file may partially duplicate the separate secretary's and president's correspondence for her years in those offices. The files are arranged chronologically under each office.
- Series VI: MEMBERSHIP APPLICATIONS AND CORRESPONDENCE, 1947-77
  The files are arranged alphabetically by member or potential member name and include correspondence with or about that individual, applications, clippings, and a few photographs. It is unclear whether these files were maintained by various officers, the Governing Committee, the Membership Committee, or all of the above. This series also contains several folders of correspondence and miscellaneous items regarding membership in general. Membership matters are also addressed in the Officer's Correspondence (Series V).
- Series VII: COMMITTEES, 1949-77
  This series includes correspondence and related materials of the Legislative, Girl Scout Project, Public Relations, and Publicity committees, most of it from the 1970s. Many other ACRW committees, e.g., Service, Archives, and Finance, are represented only by their reports which appear in the minutes (Series III).
- Series VIII: PUBLICATIONS, 1967-77
  The Bulletin is the irregular ACRW newsletter. Some issues are missing from the series.
- Series IX: PHOTOGRAPHS, 1968
  This series contains color snapshots, some black and white glossies, and a few slides of the 1968 spring and fall meetings. Photographs of a few individual members are found in the Member Files (Series VI). The Scrapbooks (Series X) include pre-1968 photographs.
- Series X: HISTORY, 1944-68
  This series contains one long and several brief histories of the ACRW compiled between 1944 and 1956, as well as a short report of the first meeting in 1944, and five scrapbooks. Three were maintained by the Scrapbook Committee; two were compiled by individual members.
- Series I. CONSTITUTION AND BYLAWS, 1945, 1948, 1956, 1971
  - Bylaws and roster, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and amended bylaws, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bylaws amendments, 1956, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Series II. CODEBOOKS, 1955-73
  - Codebook, October 4, 1955
    - Revised 1961, pt. 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Revised 1961, pt. 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Revised 1968, pt. 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Revised 1968, pt. 2 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Revisions 1970-73, pt. 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Revisions 1970-73, pt. 2 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series III. MINUTES, 1945-76
  - Governing Committee Minutes
    - 1947/48-1955/56 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1956/57-1960/61 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1961/62-1964/65 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1965/66-1969/70 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1970/71-1974/75 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 1976/77 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous minutes, agendas, and memoranda, 1956-59 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General Minutes
    - First meeting, March 15, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Second meeting, October 10-11, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Eighth annual meeting, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Regional and ninth annual meeting, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Tenth annual meeting, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Eleventh annual meeting, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Twelfth annual meeting, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Thirteenth annual meeting, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Fourteenth annual meeting, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Spring and fifteenth annual meetings, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Sixteenth annual meeting, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Seventeenth annual meeting, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Spring and eighteenth annual meetings, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Spring and nineteenth annual meetings, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Twentieth annual meeting, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Twenty-first annual meeting, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Twenty-second annual meeting, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Twenty-third annual meeting, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Spring and twenty-fourth annual meetings, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Spring and twenty-fifth annual meetings, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Spring and twenty-sixth annual meetings, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Spring and twenty-seventh annual meetings, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Spring and twenty-eighth annual meetings, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Spring and twenty-ninth annual meetings, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Spring and thirtieth annual meetings, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Spring and thirty-first annual meetings, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Thirty-second annual meeting, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Thirty-third annual meeting committee reports, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Series IV: MEETING FILES, 1947-77
  - Programs and menus, 1947-55 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Programs and menus, 1956-58 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Spring meeting, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Annual meeting, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Programs and menus, 1960-67 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Silver anniversary meeting, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Spring meeting, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Annual meeting, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Spring meeting, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Annual meeting, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Spring meeting, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Annual meeting, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Spring meeting, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Annual meeting, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Spring meeting, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Annual meeting, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Annual meeting, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Annual meeting, 1977, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Series V: OFFICERS' CORRESPONDENCE, 1951-77
  - President
    - 1951-57 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Jan-Jul, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Aug-Dec, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1959 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 1960-76 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Juva Dennis
    - 1969-75 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - 1976-77 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Secretary
    - 1960, 1968-69 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1971-72 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - 1973-74 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Treasurer's reports and correspondence, 1957-59, 1972-77 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Series VI: MEMBERSHIP APPLICATIONS AND CORRESPONDENCE, 1947-77
  - A-E (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Andrews, Iva (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Arbuthnot, Gene (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Arehart, Marjorie (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Armistead, Anne (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Beauchamp, Lily (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Beckham, Ioan (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Beebe, Jane (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Bernhagen, Edna (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Bock, Emma (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Boeckman, Alison (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Boehm, Berenece (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Boyden, Laura (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Brown, Lu (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Brundick, Matilda (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Burchard, Lauretta (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Canavan, Betty (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Caplinger, Norma Jean (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Carroll, Kathleen (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Churchill, Phyllis (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Clarke, Grace (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Cobb, Harriet (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Cook, Ruth (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Copper, Joyce (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Cosentino, Mary (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Creagan, Helen (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Croy, Frances (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Cullen, Mary Louise (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Cummings, Lenora (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Darney, Elizabeth (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Dennis, Juva (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Dennis, Olive (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - DeVille, Inez (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Dobes, Minnie (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Donahue, Alice (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Dorsett, Mary (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Drechsler, Mildred (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Dugan, Marjorie (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Elvert, Vera (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Entringer, Rosemary (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Evans, Freda (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - F-K (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Ferguson, Elva (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Fleming, Ruth (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Forrest, Neoma (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Forsythe, Cora (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Fratesi, Louise (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Frazier, Gwen (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Gallagher, Catherine (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Gannon, Eileen (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Giles, Louise (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Gilpatrick, Jean (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Giroux, Alice (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Glafcke, Leona (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Glasper, Esther (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Gleason, Margaret (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Glover, Marjorie (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Goetz, Cecilia (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Gordon, Mary Louise (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Gray, Eleanor (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Griffin, Katherine (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Gross, Kathy Ann (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Haney, Elizabeth (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Harker, Marjorie (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Helm, Geraldine (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Hickman, Anne (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Hill, Ruby (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Hirst, Margaret (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Hoffman, Maralouise (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Holden, Margaret (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Holloway, Ethylene (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Hotton, Marie (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Howard, Dorothy (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Huedepohl, Helen (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Hughes, Beverly (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Hurley, Mary Ann (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Irwin, Margaret (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Jakeway, Mildred (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Kasiurak, Patricia (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Kehoe, Margaret (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Kelly, Anna (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Kezerian, Jennifer (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Ketchin, Ansley (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Keyes, Doris (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - Kluckhohn, Irene (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Koch, Anna (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Kowalczyk, Marie (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Krimmel, Frances (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Kyle, Charlotte (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - L-P (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Labahn, Mary (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - LaBoon, Catherine (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - LaChance, E. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Lane, Angela (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Lane, Goldie (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Lee, Charleen (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Lewis, Gertrude (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Liebman, Diane (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Logue, Dorothy (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Mahan, Mary (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Mahoney, Ruth (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Mathews, Annette (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Mavis, Vera (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - McDonald, Vee (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - McFie, Amelia (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - McKinney, Marion (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - McLaughlin, Margaret (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - McMulkin, Kathryn (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Meehan, Marjorie (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Meilleur, Frances (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Merrill, Grace (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Merriman, Catherine (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Milhelm, Carolyn (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Miller, Stella (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Mitchell, Amy (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Moore, Martha (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Morasco, Lois (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Morecock, Thelma (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Murdock, Ruth (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Myers, Wanda (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - O'Mara, C. (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Parker, Irene (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Patton, Janet (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Pechtel, Dorothy (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Perkins, Elaine (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Peterson, Helen (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Peterson, Irene (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Petterson, Elsie (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Phelon, Marjorie (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Phillips, Esther (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Porter, Hazel (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Power, Evelyn (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Poynter, Wandaleen (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Prall, Inez (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Prond, Lillian (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - Pulaski, Marie (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - R-Z (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Randall, Charlotte (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Reitz, Joan (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Richardson, Ellen (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Rieder, Martha (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Rieke, Irene (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Reilly, Virginia (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Reynolds, Grace (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Robinson, Betsy (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Rogers, Carolyn (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Ross, Lillian (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Royon, Betty (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Sadler, Jean (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Sargent, Liz (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Sheahan, Madeleine (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Silverman, Sheila (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Smilie, Emily (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Soltes, Cynthia (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Stanley, Priscilla (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Stevenson, Ann (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Stivers, Margaret (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Stone, Edith (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Stone, Shirley (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Streza, Martha (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Sullivan, Catherine (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Swallow, Geraldine (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Tanner, Virginia (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Tartas, Elizabeth (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Tuczkus, Ann (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Vaupotic, Virginia (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Walker, Josephine (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Walker, Mary (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Warden, Louise (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Wetterlin, Ruth (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Whitney, Jane (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Williams, Hazel (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Williams, Marie (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Wilson, Nora (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Winslow, Isobel (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Yarwood, Margaret (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Zack, Lucille (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - General correspondence
    - 1953-57 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - 1967-1971 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 1975-1977 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Rosters and other lists, 1957-77, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Survey, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Forms and miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Series VII: COMMITTEES, 1949-77
  - Committee chairs, 1968-69 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Legislative Committee
    - America's Sound Transportation Review Organization (ASTRO), 1971-73, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - ERA Resolution and International Women's Year Commission, 1975-76 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Dam and Lock Resolution, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Coal Slurry Resolution, 1976-77 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous, 1952, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Public Relations Committee
    - Reports and correspondence, 1973, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Operation Lifesaver, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Publicity Committee
    - Press releases and clippings, 1949-69 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Press releases, clippings, and correspondence, 1972-77 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Girl Scout Project Committee, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
- Series VIII: PUBLICATIONS, 1967-77
  - ACRW Bulletin
    - Nov 15, 1967-Dec 8, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Jan 13, 1971-Dec 1973 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Jan 1974-Dec 1975 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Feb 13, 1976-Aug 1977 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Series IX: PHOTOGRAPHS, 1968
  - Spring meeting, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Fall meeting, reception and banquet, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Fall meeting, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Series X: HISTORY, 1944-68
  - "Docket Report" (first meeting of railroad industry women), 1944 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Brief histories, 1949, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "History of the National Association of Railroad Women" (additions "history of ACRW," 1952 on), 1944-56 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Volume I, 1949-59 (Box 17)
    - Volume II, 1959-63 (Box 17)
    - Volume III, 1963-68 (Box 18)
    - 1948-54 (kept by Virginia Vaupotic) (Box 18)
    - (kept by Marion McKinney)1948-53 (Box 18)